all right greetings everyone it is
October 10th 1010
23 and we're in our discussion of
chapter 7 so last week Ali and I
recorded like the short video overviews
of chapters nine and 10 just because
there was um only a few of us during our
cohort for slot and we just wanted to
complete those um overviews so now we're
in the chapter
7 um discussion so we'll jump over to
the chapter 7
page um and before we look at like any
of the specific questions like does
anybody just want to
share
um what did they think about chapter 7
what what was there impression or
or how would they summarize it to to
somebody or what was just exciting to
them about chapter
7 well can I start
um
so
please
hello Daniel hi yeah go forward go
forward yeah so so my um impression of
chapter 7 is about
uh uh it's many about about the uh
discrete uh
State and discrete outcome model of the
active
inference
and I found it is particularly uh useful
to have a detail understanding
of one of the example which is this
T's uh
example and it is kind of the first uh
active inference model that I can get my
hand on and try it out and change those
uh those parameters or the the matrixes
used in the active inference model and
see how
um how the uh active inference uh
actually
works awesome I think that's kind of the
point
um anyone else want to give a thought on
seven um yeah I would just second
everything that uh Lan said just now um
I think it's a great way to actually see
maybe how some of the the ideas that
we've been reading about prior in the
textbook actually start to hang together
and play out in an example I think that
the the use of discret variables is
highly like kind of interpretable I
think this is a it comes a little bit
more naturally to me to read this
chapter
versus um you know chapter 8 uh with
continuous variables because we get to
see like your you know more precise
specific things that happen discreet
choices and and things that occur and
then also just some kind of interesting
observations that come out of that with
the different um kind of components of
the model like uh you know as you get
further in the chapter there's a
discussion of like here are the
interesting things that happen whenever
you don't include preferences or have
highly uh uniform preferences like
there's just pure novelty seeking on the
part of the agent who like um like in
the team's example they just can't sit
still they never come back to the same
spot they just it's pure just seeking
epistemic value it seems because there's
nothing pragmatic to do because there's
nothing in particular that they're going
for because it's not been hardcoded into
the initialized um preferences so so
yeah just um giving us that that really
big model for active inference here in
the discret form in addition seeing the
interesting dynamics that can kind of
play out emerging properties and so
on
awesome anyone else want to make a
general comment on
seven I would I would just Echo that
given that I've come from a psychology
background and so seeing the exploration
exploitation Paradigm just being laid
out in that way and they make the
comment that you know they believe
they've
uh come to understand how these two go
hand in hand instead of being
competitive I thought that was also very
very
intuitive cool yes yeah the continuous
time setting is kind of like having your
hand on the rudder in a
boat and uh so you're making continuous
actions and there's a continuous flow in
these paths
and the discreete time is like chess or
Checkers
like time
clicks discreetly and the actions are
discreet the states are discreet and so
that can make it kind of clearer a
little bit more cut and dry
um cool does anybody want to jump to a
specific section of seven or we can look
at the questions and just like look at
at the upvoted ones or if anybody
submitted any and just like look at
what's interesting in
seven or or somebody can propose a
section that that they want to look
at I'm yeah I'm mostly interest see in
chapter uh
uh
7.3 uh decision making and planning as a
reference uh I wonder if you know if
someone else has preference to talk
about the sure well
let's yeah let's get to 7.3 basically
7.1 is just one paragraph we can see
here 7.2 is just a passive inference
model this is just the downstairs
section of the discrete time model model
we have hidden States changing through
time being related to observations at
each time point and a prior so it's just
the downstairs of figure
4.3 and it's kind of worked out in
multiple stages with this music
listening example so then we get to
7.3 now we take that downstairs the part
that looks like an
e um and we add in the action so
so this is where we actually get active
inference and then what makes it active
inference under the free energy
principle is that the unified imperative
for Action selection is going to be
expected free energy so right because
there are other models that have um
sense making or signal processing on the
inbound and then decision- making or
action selection or control theory on
the outbound
like that is in a loose sense active
inference but when we're talking about
active inference we're talking about
active inference and the free energy
principle which is what we get when we
bring in the variational and the
expected free energy okay so what what
aspect of 7.3 do you want to
explore well first about this figure
that you're are showing here um I I have
a question about uh the fourth line from
the
bottom uh you you see third while c and
e appear in the panel on the right do
you see that
sentence where is the e i I couldn't
find the
E yes so e um is the Habit e represents
the prior Distribution on policies
so let's just say that we have four
affordances up down left right the E
Vector is like 0.25 0.25 0.25 0.25 so in
that
situation e conveys through its
inclusion which actions are
possible and okay by the value in E that
is the prior on
policy so
if they were all 0.25s and there was
four um
affordances then that would be like
saying those options um in the absence
of being sharpened by expected free
energy are equally likely to be
taken and
um we can look at um the the nervous
system diagram in
figure 5.4 so here's e so here on the
indirect
pathway observations are coming in
habits are being
triggered on the direct pathway we have
expected free energy
sharpening our habit
distribution that doesn't just me yeah
it doesn't just mean exaggerating it it
could upweight something like let's just
say there's a rare policy um like but a
given situation it has high epistemic
Andor pragmatic value well then you'd
hope that even though your prior on um
doing it is very low like what's the
prior on taking off your seat belt well
on a 10hour car ride it's low but then
when the car is stopped and you want to
leave that's an amazingly Salient thing
to do so e basically hosts what can be
done and in the absence of any
decision-making process the distribution
of actions to be taken and then G
sharpens
that to to to to update the policy
posterior and then the policy posterior
is where action is sampled
from I see I see from from the figure
7.3 it seems that c and e plays the same
role as f in the distribution of poliy
right they kind
of Absol R um absolutely like um free
energy expected free energy here G can
be understood as a statistical
distribution about
policy conditioned upon
CN we we just discussed why e matters
for the calculation of policy posterior
C matters because of equation
2.6 so C matters for G calculation
because C is going to decide what is of
pragmatic
value so um in that representation that
they have in
7.3 basically just
saying um policy is being computed
conditioned
upon
preference and on
habit okay so C is preference e is habit
so they they encode different uh kind of
preferences of the policies
yeah okay thank you denner that's very
very good cool yeah I mean anyone else
have like a thought on 7.3 or or a
question on 7.3 or just how how they see
it or how they interpret
it so I I have further question so again
on this figure 7.3 so we see the policy
Pi affects the um the the um probity uh
State probity transition Matrix
B uh I wonder uh if it's possible to
model the uh policy also affect the
Matrix a meaning that it it it not only
affects the perp transition mes Matrix
but also um affects the transformation
from the uh state to the
outcome great great question all all
kind of mention two ways that you could
think about that so as you mentioned
policy intervenes in B how things change
through time like when you turn on the
air conditioner it doesn't like reach
into the room and just like modify the
thermometer it modifies how the
temperature changes through time so it
modifies the Dynamics of the Hidden
State the temperature and then that
results in a thermometer changing so
first answer to the question
is we don't need policy to change a if
we want if we prefer it to be cooler and
we take the policy to turn on the air
conditioner then at in the next time
step the temperature of the room is
going to drop let's say one policy is
you know turn on the air conditioner
temperature drops by one turn off it it
goes up by one so you turn it on the
temperature drops in the room and then
the the thermometer is cooler so one
answer is you don't really want to touch
a because the mapping between hidden
States and
observations isn't really something you
can act on directly and so we're
intervening in the real underlying
hidden causal
process and then that emits OB the first
and the second answer is you could
develop an active inference model where
a metacognitive agent
selects which a matrix to
use so um
maybe you decide whether to put on
sunglasses or not and then when you have
sunglasses
on colors are mapped to your vision this
way and when you do something different
they're mapped a different way so that
would be taking a policy choice on which
a to
use okay
but in most settings the relationship
between hidden States and
observations is um it's orthagonal to or
you could say it's factorized away from
how hidden States change through
time keeping this model sparse in the
sense that keeping as few edges as
possible keeps the comput ational cost
low and keeps the um kind of parsimony
High let's see thanks than that's very
good so
um yeah so so it really depends on how
the
states and the outcomes are are
defined
um maybe in my case we can Define it
such way that that high the policy
affects only the states transition
perity not affecting the
um the trans Nation from the state to
outcomes yeah in in almost all
cases you will have policy only
intervening in B so making a generative
model I mean this chapter six making a
generative model is if you can describe
what all of these are in your system of
interest you literally have the
generative model and how do you
categorize different things that you
have or want to include into this well
observations are literally the data if
it's in a spreadsheet it's literally an
observation then right policies are
actions so if something is something
that an agent can do and then everything
else is a hidden
State now if you're in a fully
observable situation like a
chessboard then it can seem like there's
a
redundancy like the observation is the
location of the piece and the hidden
state is the true location of the
piece so in that case it's not really a
partially observable Markov decision
process pomdp it's just an
mdp because it's a fully observable
decision process but a allows us to
bring in the partial
observability but if you're in a fully
observable
setting then you you can almost think
about direct
intervention however even in that case
then the a matrix is just an identity
Matrix like it Maps perfectly between
hidden States you know you have an
accurate thermometer 37 just maps to 37
then a is an identity Matrix and it has
basically no computational
cost and then your model is more
flexible in case you ever did have a
noisy thermometer or a missing
measurement if you had a
pmdp then it's fine but if you were to
only have the mdp then you can't deal
with the noisy or a partially observable
setting yes thank you thank you Dan
that's very detailed
exper
yeah I'll hold on uh hold my questions
for okay other participants to ask yeah
anyone want to just give a a thought or
or a question on this
section um yeah I guess just since it's
it's been a bit since I actually read
like really did a deep dive on this
particular chapter um but um I just I'm
trying to make sure I grasp like
whenever they're describing the the
teamas shortly after um yeah I guess
we're still in 7.3 they just start to
describe like the a matrices is like in
this case they become
tensors um like with the teamat you have
there are outcomes and then there are
locations and then there are contexts so
I guess the you know the the mouse uh
searching for a reward is looking for I
guess the outcome is like whether the
the space they land on is a reward or
not um and um the location is just you
know them navigating the maze itself and
the locations of the Maze and then also
you have the the context I might have I
might be mixing those up a bit but it's
just
just trying to make sure I can grasp
like we're looking at potentially 3D 4D
and so on um like kind of tensor um you
know quantities here that are based on
all of the kind of Dimensions to what
what the the mouse is doing rather than
just uh yeah looking at as like a 2d
thing as As Nice and simple as that
would
be yes um
ba basically yes so a I mean you could
think of it as okay well pull back the
context is whether you're in um world
State a or World State B so the two
contexts are whether the the food is on
the left or the right um in in in in in
this setting you just you did mention
that um okay so now a Maps between
observations and hidden stat States
there's going to be two types of hidden
States and so each of them projects out
to a given
observation
A1 is about location A2 is about
context I don't know if you would
properly call this a
tensor but certainly this is two
matrices um but it it's not but they're
different shapes this is a 5x5 Matrix
and this is a a a 3x4 matrix when we get
to B it will be a true tensor in the
sense that every slice of B is going to
be a matrix with the same
dimensionality but here it's kind of
like two parallel channels like this
would be analogous to having two sensory
modalities so if if we had had vision
and hearing those a
matrices um could map to the same hidden
State like maybe you know is there
lightning um or is is there a
thunderstorm and you might have a
mapping between hearing and is there a
thunderstorm um and vision and is there
a thunderstorm or you can have those two
observation
modalities maap to two different hidden
State modalities like in this case I
just want to make one more point before
we continue um forward in the teas
because um it was brought up about the
explore
exploit the most probable policies are
those that lead to the lowest expected
free energy again this is one of the key
distinguishing features if not the key
distinguishing feature between active
inference guided policy select ction and
reinforcement learning or reward
maximization there is no proposal of
a reward or utility function that gets
optimized there's just the definition of
the generative model and then the
generative model does the likeliest
thing given its setup again that doesn't
mean the animal lives it doesn't mean
that XYZ
it just means that given how the
generative model is set up it does the
likeliest thing and then given
empirical data chapter nine we set up or
parameterize the generative model to be
the likeliest
one so Daniel can yeah go Ahad sorry
yeah I I do have a question regarding
744 where you're right there yeah here
uh so I'm I be confused what p and Q
means um do we always use P represents
the uh prior or the true distribution
and Q as a approximate distribution Q is
is is this Q the one we actually want uh
the
decision that we uh we intend to um to
change our belief by
updating uh
approximation to the uh real real
probability so p is the real probability
exactly Q is the real mapping in this
case um so it's it's a natural log so
this is kind of like taking a
surprisal okay it's a it's
of observations conditioned upon
preferences so this is really what What
You observe in relationship to what you
prefer you and the reason why it it has
the p is because we're talking about
like the the actual
observations coming in and Q is the
variational distribution that we
control okay okay yeah now it's clear so
actually we can change Q to minimize
this GQ GP this object function here
right yeah um yeah like Q are about our
beliefs whereas we don't really get to
control in the same way like we Q of
observations conditioned upon policy so
what do I believe the sequence of future
observations will be ilda conditioned
upon what I do that's all in the
mind that is different than
what is the sequence of observations
given my
preferences you can change your
preferences but that doesn't change
observations given your preferences and
similarly you could change your belief
about hidden States but you can't in the
same way control the mapping between
observations and hidden States in
actuality yeah and this is like a
restatement in equation 7.4 of equation
2.6 expected free energy so we have same
epic and pragmatic value okay so let's
go through the teamas and just see how
this is going to play out okay so the
two factors so factor is being used to
describe a different kind of hidden
State um so again there's two factors
here there's the context factor and the
location factor
one of those is a controllable Factor
location
whereas context is not a controllable
Factor if it were there would be another
policy
type change the food to the left to the
right but we're not in that setting so
this example brings up the distinction
between controllable and uncontrollable
factors
observations they are the fundamental
observables that's in the spreadsheet
then everything that's not an
observation is a hidden State Factor
State factor and then some State factors
are controllable those are the ones that
have policies intervening in their B
matrices other state factors are
uncontrollable it's just a latent cause
of the world that's proposed within a
cognitive model but with respect to that
uncontrollable State Factor that's like
listening to music the first example
that's like a passive inference on that
state
Factor okay so the controllable state
are the are the uh are the locations of
the mouse right right because it can
move uncontrollable states are the
locations of this
yeah because the mouse doesn't get to
decide where the food
is right yeah okay yeah um so that then
that's where agency and self-efficacy
can come into play
is to what extent do actions bear
upon
um Can can the agent take actions and
make a difference that makes a
difference take an action that changes
some state in the world controllable
factor
and how are and then this is all about
how they evaluate that it could be
chosen because it has high pragmatic
value because doing that kind of
exerting that kind of control brings
observations closer to alignment with
preferences pragmatic value
or it might lead to new information
about the world epistemic value and
that's the entropy the
expected
difference of the
entropies
of observations conditioned upon hidden
States in comparison with
observations conditioned upon
policy so this is basically like the
entropy of the a
matrix so that's that's the mapping
between observations in Hidden States
here we're asking how much is it going
to matter differently if we condition
upon policy so let's just say that the a
matrix has a a given entropy the a
matrix has a given uncertainty
associated with it the least uncertain a
matrix is like the identity Matrix just
one on the diagonal and all zeros
elsewhere you have perfect knowledge it
becomes a fully observable setting the
most entropy a matrix is just All
Uniform basically the measurements don't
even matter because all the measurements
are equally likely to map to any hidden
state so that's on the left side and now
the question is conditioned upon
action is there going to be a difference
in the sharpness of that mapping well if
it's a policy that doesn't lead to
sharpening of the a it doesn't have
episte IC value in comparison if there's
a policy such
that um you believe that taking that
policy is going to sharpen your
understanding of
outcomes then this is a non-zero
value so that's the epistemic
value yes Daniel the um however you said
that you know from the model that a
matrix is is fixed right it's not affect
by you know all the entries in a matrix
are not affected by the PCY Pi because
PCY Pi affects only the state transition
probability Matrix
B and what do you mean by sharpen a
using policy
Pi good question so there's there's a
few um a few pieces here first off
there's a matrix learning that is not
happening in this example so okay but
but but but but it is it is a cognitive
phenomena that the a matrix could be
updated but it's not being there's no
learning here um now let's just say that
there's um we have we have a a two
observ we have observations and and
hidden States one of the
observations doesn't lead to gain
information about hidden
States like it Maps 50% of the time to A
or B another observation gives you a lot
of information uh information about the
world then that
policy can the policy that that leads
you to get that OB the informative
observation that has a high um epistemic
value
now that doesn't mean that policy
reaches into
a in the factorization of the base
graph right so it's it's not like every
single thing it's like saying well um
how could what the finger does influence
the
knee they're not connected directly it's
like well yeah but the whole generative
model is executed as a
whole so um
you can I mean to put it a different way
you can use expressions in the active
inference
ontology that associate different
variables that aren't necessarily
connected through an edge
here so these edges are not the only
possible sentences that you can
construct when talking about the
generative
model so you can talk about how G is
related to O right OB obviously because
observations are what are o Tilda are
what are being taken into account when
we're talking about G but there's no
line between G and
observations so this is just asking
um will those observations be
informative and and the observations
being
informative doesn't need to entail
update of the a
matrix I see I see yeah good point good
yeah or you know there there's two
people you can ask one of them he flips
a coin the other one right tells you the
truth so the epistemic value with going
to the person who gives you the good
information is
high even if you have a fixed
understanding of that
situation okay let's look at it in the
team A's
setting yeah yeah okay okay so so
technically okay technically the a
matrices are
tensors but it's a little bit of an
irregular
one okay so here we have these two kind
of parallel
A's on the the first and the second
[Music]
um uh context of a or first and the
second
factors mapping
um the actual
location here on the rows note that
there's this L and the
r this is because the hidden states are
in the cases of being on the right being
on the left and being in the starting
position those are all identity mappings
but now because we're in the black on
the right
setting the epistemic Q at the bottom
when you are physically in the bottom
you go to the hidden state which tells
you you're in the r context and there's
all zeros here that hidden State cannot
be reached but of course when the
context is Switched it's the exact
opposite there's a one here going to the
bottom Maps you to the it's the L State
and there is no way to reach the r
State and we also see a flipping of the
98s 98 is here on the bottom left and on
the right and here it's on the top left
on the right this is again just just to
show these matrices are necessary and
sufficient for specifying the
situation they describe literally
exactly what is happening all that your
generative model knows is what you
specify in these matrices there's no
other
information
so that's the a matrix this these this
is showing the two
contexts and it's
showing um the mappings
between um
location
and this kind of
like location
plus distinction between the messages
that the epistemic Q on the bottom could
provide and then also notice that um
when you're in the starting or the
bottom
position you're you're in the sort of
like dashed line like you're not finding
out anything but then when you're in but
then there's a 98% chance you have a 98%
sensory
accuracy there still is a 2%
mapping between um you know um if you
know if you're on the left in this
context and it's black there's there's
still a 2% chance it maps to
White
okay now we get to B so similarly we're
going to have two B
matrices um or two B tensors for each of
these State
factors B2 they're going to introduce
first because B2 the context stays
constant over time and can be
represented as an identity Matrix so
basically this is just keeping the same
thing through time within a
trial and this is where we get the the
true B
tensor
here this describes
location
changes as a function of movement
selection so we have from and to and
then there's four
[Music]
actions
um
B does all the
work let's look at the generative model
like observations are just data points
hidden states are hidden States um
they're they're just descriptors
proposed or actual Laten descriptors and
then this is just a sensory
mapping but all the work of the meaning
of embedded action is going to play out
through
b the dimensionality of
B is also higher because B is whatever
the dimensionality is of the state
Factor then as many slices as there are
policies yeah because each
policy is going
to change how the world changes now if
all of these slices were the
same that would be like saying whichever
policy you select the world is going to
change in the same way so in that
situation there's no real causal
efficacy or agency of that
agent yes so B is really where it's at
and and in this example the B is just
given and fixed but there are other
examples that we could explore that you
can look up where there's B Matrix
learning so that's learning the
consequences of one's
actions through taking different
policies so that's a situation kind of
like a a multi-armed band it where you
actually have to learn the
mapping between different
things
um
preferences here C2 is the um the
context Associated preference
Vector so we have uh if there's new the
dashed line is neutral so this is these
three elements corresp
respond to these three elements 0 6
negative and
six and then these
five in the top C correspond to these
five um and then as they say there's
there's a slight they give a negative
one to the starting position just to
kind of bump it off and get it going
because if it really had no
preferences it it I
mean all of this comes into the
parameterization why is it six and not
nine and negative 9 why not nine and -2
that is the parameterization question so
when we're in a pedagogical setting and
we're just like looking to play around
that's when it's super helpful to have
the the code and like do parameter
sweeps or just by hand play around with
how different variables change the
outcome of the model um and then in
chapter nine it discusses more well how
would you go from a bunch of videos of
rats in the
Maze to inferring what the likeliest
parameters
are but here they're just
given um also just note that these
values
are given in
um a way that it's actually like e to
the
blank so the six
here has um actually a a
very
interpretable
meaning in terms of the ratio of the
preference so this is not just like six
arbitrary
points or like I don't know it is just
literally describing kind of like the
the odds
ratio
right
d in the
context um domain it's just one2 one
one or it could have just said 0. 5.5
but they're they're
conveying that it has to sum to one
something must happen this is a
distribution and the values are the
same so uniform
distribution this is a perfect knowledge
over the starting
position right Daniel can ask a question
here
so this D2 is half and half perity right
but this is not known to the agent who
makes the active inference right it is
known it it starts
out completely unsure it starts out with
a 50-50 belief but it's kind of funny
because it's like it's 100%
sure that it's
50/50
like same as a coin flip you're 100%
sure that it's
50/50 if you had a more sophisticated
model and and it is shown in a later
figure you could have a hyper
prior on D so you could ask how
confident am I about the prior you can
do that for any of
them okay okay so you have a hyper prior
that can uh characterize
D2 uh maybe character as some parameter
right so you can later on learn learn
those
parameters
exactly exactly any parameter that you
want to
learn in a bayian statistic setting you
need a hyper
prior if you don't if have if it's just
a fixed
parameter then it's like the equivalent
of the derac Delta
function it's just like a spike like you
have like it's just like a single
observation right yeah um and and it's
always a very interesting thing in this
case or in in your own generative models
like what is being made
explicit and then what is actually being
kept implicit for example like how does
the rat
know that it's going to get the
information at that
location right more more question how
does the r know it's half and a half
it's just given it's just given I mean
that's like asking how how does the rat
know that moving um to the left is going
to get it to the
left but but also um keep the uh figure
figure 9.2
in
mind weird it's like it
can't
9.1 we're making a map of the Rat here
is literally figure four figure 4.3 or
figure 7.3 right there D is not
shown so we're just describing its map
of its space we're not claiming to make
a total account of everything that the
rat
knows
um but yeah I mean we there's more to
say on this example then there's an i
example here's here in 710 here's the
prior on
D here's the lowercase letters or hyper
everything
then another example with a maze finding
agent and then a
hierarchical nested model where you you
put a
GM as a leaf in another
GM and that is shown in a nested example
so it's kind of a long chapter
actually but there because there's a lot
of examples that are kind of like
densely packed but just in our last like
minutes here what what does anyone find
interesting or what questions they still
have well um I still have one more
question in in the in the end of section
7.3
okay
um uh so it's uh two sentence above
7.4
okay yeah you're still at uh
okay okay um for I think further up um
so it talks about the neuron neuronal
activity uh okay yeah so the second to
the last sentence
uh it talk about field potentials and
neural
activities right uh in figure
7.2 yeah um so so my question is how
realistic is this um Chim
model uh comparing to the experimental
data so we have this is ass simulation
right so basically we constructed active
uh inference model using the data to
simulate the activities of the of of a
mouse in in the
tmat uh so my question is how does the
simulation results compare to the uh
actual biological experiment the
activities of the mouse and how they um
the brain the mouse brain
um uh activities you know uh imply or or
corresponds to this numerical
simulation I'm not aware of them doing
this in a rat doing the te- but it may
exist we should look it up in other
settings it Maps very very
well now that's just like from from my
perspective it's just a bonus because
active inference is not developed as an
account of brains the particular
partition the basian mechanics all of
the cognitive physics doesn't need to be
about any specific system however as the
empirical lines of work have shown
various features of the model that are
very
non-trivial are recapitulated in
Biometrics that suggests that the
analytical solution and the biological
embodiment have a convergence strategy
an example of that is predictive coding
predictive coding was invented by
humans as a way to do video encoding
because it turns out that frame
differencing is the most efficient way
to do video encoding like instead of
just trying to compress every frame you
basically compress the B Matrix because
if something doesn't change you don't
even need to mention it in the next
slide so right predictive coding was a
purely information theoretic
consideration but it turned out to be
utilized in neural coding
situations
so I see it as positive where it aligns
but um where it doesn't align
then it it it it ALS it
doesn't it just means that there's
something else happening that that isn't
just narrowly
that yeah because you see in figure 7.2
they show the neural activities and the
fireing Rays and local field potentials
so there must be some mechanism to
translate the outcome of the numerical
simulation into those neuro activities
right the the biological uh uh
embodiment of the numerical size um so
through what mechanism do they uh trans
transform this numerical into into the
uh into the field potentials for example
neuro
activities yeah it's all in the mat lab
code in the mat laab functions that are
used it describes it in more detail but
basically the lfps are associated with
with belief
updating how about fire race are they
associal with yeah decision you could
imagine different different firing rates
or different different I mean and this
has been studied extensively in the fmri
and EEG
setting um you know does does the um Erp
in the ERG or does the local field
potential associate with a more intense
stimuli with a more expected stimuli
with the less expected stimuli with
learning those are all hypotheses that
people have
explored and for different stimuli in
different
settings you see different patterns
[Music]
okay any last um comments
here um I mean I I don't want to keep us
too long but I just yeah I
still as the last bit I find the
Novelties
seeking uh rather interesting like just
the example it's roughly around page 145
146 like if you were to
model give it like if there were an
absence of preferences for an agent then
like I'm just quoting here the drive to
novelty resolution given by expected
free energy minimization leads our
simulated creature to avoid any
previously visited
locations um just like you know it
becomes like a purely like the model is
attempting to uh resolve expected free
energy if I understand this correctly by
just it's just seeking more and more
information it's going to places it
hasn't been before um there's nothing
pragmatic about returning to previous
places it's not attempting to realize
any preferences that say I need to go
back right so I just thought that's a
really nice kind of kind of emergent
property that we see whenever you leave
out preferences here and it it for me it
it kind of lays a lot of emphasis on
like the importance of of preferences
they're impact upon behavior in these
models and just maybe makes me think of
like how to you know maybe start with
preferences how to model those
appropriately because it can highly
impact um right like an agent's Behavior
yep great points and the strength of the
preferences
overall and and where that ends up on a
Continuum between novelty seeking and
basically ruthless pragmatic
indeed all right thank you all um we go
into chapter eight next time in the
later time slot so peace till next time
bye thank you Daniel Day